HWANG DAESIK
For crying out loud.
Not a single one of those so-called
government ministers ever comes prepared.
I swear.
They should have everything ready
before I even say a word.
Advisor Jang, what brings you here
at the crack of dawn?
General, you're attending
the ten o'clock meeting today, right?
Yeah.  Oh, God.
I don't know
if it's the season,
but I feel like crap.
So, um, what about the meeting?
Well, since you're
a little under the weather,
why don't you take break on this one?
What? You think I should cancel it?
Oh, no. Today's meeting…
must start on schedule.
At 10:00 a.m. sharp.
Is this C-4?
-  Miss Oh.
- Yes?
Has Captain Min Jonghwan come in yet?
No, haven't seen him today.
Miss Oh.
I'm gonna tell you something
very important.
Listen carefully.
Min is gonna have…
a bomb with him today.
A… A bomb? Really?
Min has arrived for the meeting.
Let's move, then.
Miss Oh.
Let's keep this strictly
between the two of us…
until we've apprehended Baek Kitae.
Do you know where General Hwang is?
Present arms!
Yes, sir!
HWANG DAESIK
Min just arrived in the office.
What about Colonel Baek?
I didn't see him around earlier.
Are you looking
for something, ma'am?
Where are you going?
Captain Min.
Captain, hey.
Ah. Yes, sir.
So, did you manage
to get what I asked you for?
Oh, yes, sir. I have it here.
PERSONAL RECORD
Thank you. New briefcase, huh?
Uh, yeah. Someone gave it to me.
Oh, nice.
American-made.
How 'bout that. Made in the USA.
- How do you open this thing?
- Uh, sorry.
I have a meeting soon.
Excuse me.
Have a good day, sir.
Captain Min.
Yes, sir.
You gonna grab a seat?
I was gonna have a smoke
before the meeting.
All right.
When you're ready,
set the combination lock
on the left side of the briefcase
to three, eight, six.
Once you do, the circuit will activate,
and it will automatically arm
the detonator connected to the lock.
After exactly ten minutes,
the bomb will go off.
The lethal blast radius
is about 20 meters,
so leave it by your seat
and get out of there.
-  Colonel Ahn.
- Yes, sir.
From now on,
let's schedule these in the afternoon.
I haven't even had breakfast yet.
Understood, sir.
Where's the commander?
Don't worry, he's coming.
Captain Min.
Yes, sir?
The meeting is gonna start soon.
Where are you going?
Um, I was going to go get the report.
Stop! Don't move, you bastard!
Everyone, stay where you are.
Colonel Ahn.
Get everybody out.
Are we evacuating?
Everybody needs to leave the room now!
It's an emergency. Get out!
- Get out of here now.
-  What the hell is going on?
I'll explain later, sir. Hey, make sure
the Chief of Staff gets out. Hurry!
- Move it, let's go!
-  Come on, hurry.
Get him out of here now!
- Move it!
-  Hey…
Geez.
You too, Ahn.
Yeah.
And you, Miss Oh.
Let's go, asshole.
Come on.
Get out.
I'm not seeing a red wire.
You said he was
supposed to be in this car!
Sir. Wait.
- Sir! We've got JIH vehicles incoming.
- Kihyun.
Director Baek, it's a trap, sir.
- We have to go right now.
- Kihyun.
What are you doing here? Come on, Kihyun.
- Stop, wait. Kihyun!
- We have to go.
Kihyun, you're all right.
Hey, Kihyun. Get off me, asshole.
- Hey, Kihyun! Wake up!
-  Sir, we have to go.
-  We have to go.
- Kihyun, wake up! Kihyun!
Wake up!
- Kihyun! Wake up, damn it!
-  Keep moving.
- Hey, cover him!
-  Kiyhun! Kihyun, please!
They're coming.
Sir, we have to go now.
- Sir, please.
- Wake up, for God's sake!
- Get the hell off me! Kihyun!
-  Cover him, you idiots! Hey!
- Get in the car, sir. Shut the door.
- Kihyun, no!
You little rat.
Damn you.
Oh. Oh.
Oh, shit. I'm so screwed.
General.
Did you get him? Baek Kitae?
He escaped.
It'd be a lot better for us…
if that asshole was just dead.
Long as he's breathing, he's a liability.
Yes, sir. Copy that.
Goddamn.
If Jang hadn't told me,
I would've wound up dead, right?
Baek Kitae, that bastard.
I don't believe it!
All right. I'm gonna…
I'm gonna head over
to the safe house for now.
Stay put and make sure everything's okay.
- Got it?
-  I'll get the car ready, sir.
-  Yeah, let's go.
- Hang on, wait a minute.
What?
I think that Baek Kihyun
should be sent there before you.
Baek Kihyun?
Him first?
Trust me on this, General.
Baek Kitae's dangled bait
in front of me before.
And if you decide to take it,
you'll end up caught.
What? B-Bait?
Yes.
So what if this bomb is some kind of bait?
What do you mean, it's bait?
You think…
he'll ambush me
on the way to the safe house?
Okay. So then…
Now what? What do you recommend?
I think you should just sit tight
and enjoy a nice, big bowl
of jjajangmyeon, sir.
That's all you have to do.
What?
- Drop your head.
- Yes, sir.
Baek Kitae is a fucking bastard!
That sly little asshole is going down.
DIRECTOR BAEK KITAE
So Baek Kitae…
…made an attack
on Hwang Daesik's armored car?
Yes, sir.
And Hwang was nowhere to be found, right?
- Correct, Mr. Pyo.
- Just Baek Kihyun?
Jang Geonyoung's pretty clever, huh?
Everyone's plotting. No one's safe.
Someone's gonna have to die.
It's not gonna be me.
It better not be.
What is this?
Get him out.
Go. It's fine.
I was just going to call you.
What's going on with Baek Kitae?
Where do you think
someone like him would hide?
You lost him?
The KCIA's got a few
major safe houses, doesn't it?
I want a detailed map
with all their locations marked right now.
Let's make a deal first.
Baek Kitae is captured…
and this chair is mine.
- Where are the safe hou--
- I want your word on this first.
Why don't I…
have these soldiers drag you down
to the basement of the JIH
and we can talk there instead?
You like that option better?
Come on, don't do this.
- The safe houses.
- All right, all right.
Give me a sec.
The map's in my office.
Go with him.
Oh, look at you.
My goodness.
What happened, Chief Cheon?
Oh, gosh, you look awful right now.
I haven't heard from you for awhile.
Guess you're a little busy.
So what brings you here today, Madam Shin?
Well, you'll be glad to know
that I've been praying
day and night for you, sir.
You better be fucking kidding me
with this praying shit.
Hwang is coming.
He's out for blood, don't you get that?
Staring up at the sky and mumbling
isn't gonna solve anything.
They kick the crap out of you
and you're as blockheaded as ever.
You're such a helpless, pathetic man,
but you can't stop running your mouth.
That certainly explains
why you're still rotting in this dungeon.
Doesn't it?
Are you on drugs?
- What's the matter with you?
- All right.
You listen here, Chief Cheon.
You're not the president's
Chief of Staff anymore.
This is a completely different world now.
How can you possibly be this clueless?
Baek Kitae has a warrant out
for his arrest.
I warned you, didn't I?
General Hwang isn't the kind of man
who'll go down that easily.
That damn bald son of a bitch
is practically invincible, I swear.
Oh, stop dwelling on those thoughts.
Do you wanna stay here forever?
Madam Shin,
is there any way for me to be released?
Perhaps.
It all depends on how you play this.
This next part is crucial.
Well, look at you!
It's been a while, Chief Cheon.
Gosh, you've really been trying
to knock my block off, haven't you?
You should be thanking
Madam Shin right now.
You'd have a bullet in your skull
if it weren't for this woman here,
you son of a bitch.
The truth is, I'm only here
because of her, just so you know.
Anything you wanna share with me?
Just talk to him.
I went to a lot of trouble
to arrange this meeting.
We need to work together
to find a way to survive.
Don't you think?
Apparently he doesn't even
wanna make it through the night.
Oh, well.
How about this?
We'll put you in a shallow grave
alongside Baek Kitae…
The two of you together.
- You piece of garbage!
- General Hwang.
What do you want from me, sir?
Bang, got ya! Bang, bang!
Now that's the attitude I'm looking for.
My fellow citizens,
I'm Cheon Seokjung, Chief of Staff…
…to the president.
To begin,
I'd like to express my genuine relief
that the truth has finally come to light.
I'd also like to address
the slush fund ledger,
which has been reported on
by many media outlets.
I'd like to be clear.
The aforementioned ledger was not mine.
It is the property of KCIA Director
Baek Kitae and documents the scale…
of his elaborate criminal enterprise.
As the Joint Investigation Headquarters
intensified its inquiry
and his crimes
were on the verge of being exposed,
Acting Director Baek Kitae
committed the grave crime
of plotting the assassination
of General Hwang Daesik,
the head of the JIH
and a prominent figure in government.
Fortunately, General Hwang
uncovered this violent plot in advance
and marshaled a swift response,
foiling the attempt on his life
before it could be carried out.
I need you to tell me something.
Why do the reports all say
Cheon's money belongs to Baek Kitae?
I want Cheon close.
He could be useful in the future.
He stepped down as Chief of Staff, so…
Let's wrap this up, all right?
You think I struggled for nine years,
surviving through hell on earth,
just to crash and burn like this?
You know damn well Baek Kitae
didn't plan all this on his own.
Cheon and Baek Kitae have to go down
together to put a stop to this.
You better be careful.
I decide when
and how we end this, Advisor Jang.
Come on, Hwang, wake up!
That's enough, sir. Calm down.
Lower your gun, shithead.
I said that's enough.
Well…
…if it weren't for you, Advisor Jang,
there's no doubt I'd be dead right now.
Baek Kitae thought he was so clever.
Thought we'd never see him coming.
Sneaky bastard.
Hey.
You've done an excellent job up until now.
So I think
that you've earned yourself some rest.
What do you say?
I'll send Special Forces with you.
Find Baek and kill him
before the day is over.
Yes, sir. I'll put an end to this.
Your time's finally up, Baek Kitae.
Breaking news.
The slush fund ledger previously believed
to belong to Chief of Staff Cheon Seokjung
has now been definitively linked
to Acting KCIA Director Baek Kitae.
Earlier this morning,
as the investigation closed in on Baek,
sources say he suddenly disappeared.
Meanwhile, Chief of Staff
Cheon Seokjung has stated that
he takes full political responsibility
for the situation
and promptly announced his resignation.
Mr. Cheon also released a public statement
calling for a thorough
criminal investigation
into Acting Director Baek Kitae,
who has continued to evade authorities.
Director Baek.
I don't know how they found it,
but the JIH just raided the safe house
in Segeomjeong.
…foiling the attempt on
his life before it could be carried out.
I can say with utmost certainty,
- these developments demonstrate…
-  Sir?
…the full extent of Baek Kitae's
traitorous activities.
- His actions will no longer be concealed…
- We can't stay here much longer.
And I would be remiss in my duties
as a former government official…
Where do you wanna go?
…this great nation
if I didn't take a moment
to express my deepest possible gratitude
to General Hwang Daesik,
and call for a thorough and impartial
investigation into Baek Kitae,
who has deceived
the investigative authorities
and committed acts of heinous consequence.
So did you finish
what you had to do?
I'm sorry.
What do you need from me?
Please send a boat for me when you can.
It's an emergency.
All right.
They're sending a boat to Busan.
We're headed to Busan then?
How's Kihyun?
Any information?
Not much, sir. Sorry.
It appears he was taken
directly to the ER…
but that's as much as I've heard.
Just keep checking.
Of course, sir.
What have you got?
Well, my contact in Japan said
Choi Yuji has already left town.
As you suspected he would,
Baek Kitae is probably heading that way.
And Cheon Seokjung?
He's nowhere to be found.
EXPORT IS THE CULMINATION
OF NATIONAL POWER
Kitae.
Wha… What are you…
Look, I know.
I completely understand how you feel.
But I had no choice.
Hwang Daesik told me if I didn't obey,
he'd murder me right then and there.
What was I supposed to do?
There are no other moves to make
if you can't even ensure your survival.
If you'd taken care of Hwang Daesik,
we'd be fine by now, Baek.
Just listen, all right?
At this point, this country's gonna end up
in the hands of those Army Neanderthals.
We can't be turning on each other
right now.
If I survive, then you survive.
And so does your family.
Hwang and I talked, and we made a deal.
Do some jail time,
just a quick little stint,
and when you come back out…
we pick up where we left off
with our business.
Just trust me one more time
and we're home free.
I'm pretty much the only person
you can trust right now!
What?
You think I won't ever get this seat?
Believe me.
Before I die…
you're gonna see
that you're wrong about that.
You deserve to sit here as well.
I've always said that, right?
After me, it's you.
Kitae.
We have more cards left in the deck.
What happened to trust?
Have you ever trusted me?
That's what I thought.
Ugh, goddamn it.
Where were you? I-I, uh…
I was just trying to clear things out.
50, 71, 16.
Open it.
What's the combo?
Shit, it's hot.
Seventy-one.
- Sixteen.
This is everything?
What's wrong? Not enough?
I just expected a lot more than this.
Oh, shit.
Where did I leave it now?
Give me a break, man.
Well…
After you failed to take out Hwang,
they turned off the power here.
Turned off all utilities.
Water, too.
Shame, isn't it?
You did all the hard work,
and someone else got rich.
Cheon Seokjung took it for himself
and hung you out to dry.
Kitae.
You and I… are humble servants.
Government lackeys. Right?
We just try our best
to do what we're told.
We're both resigned to that fate.
Come on, how much power do we have?
Is that why you jumped into bed
with Jang again, you bald little rat?
It's not what you think, okay?
I'll explain it.
Just listen…
Kitae.
Don't do this.
I'll do anything you want.
I swear!
I won't ever betray you again.
I'll help you get
everything you ever wanted!
I swear to God.
Kitae.
Kitae!
Listen.
I told Jang everything.
It's all true, okay?
You're right, I told him everything.
Happy now?
I know you murdered Director General Hwang
and took his seat.
So, hey.
How are we different, huh?
Huh?
Why am I the one who has to die?
Why me? Huh? Why?
Why am I the only one?
Hey! Why am I the one who has to die?
The boat should be arriving
in three hours, sir.
We need to leave for Busan right away.
And Kihyun?
Well, sir…
Tell me.
Apparently he's in bad shape.
Baek Kihyun. How is he?
They said…
he might not make it much longer.
SEONGSAN HOSPITAL
208 - BAEK KIHYUN
You still think you're in the right?
Are you that stupid and naive?
You think by taking me down,
you're changing the world?
I guess you still don't get it.
The world has already changed.
And the thing is…
there isn't a place for you in it.
You're finished.
What about you?
Where do you fit?
I was…
serving my country.
Everything I did…
I did for the sake of this nation.
Mommy?
Are you okay?
Here, sweetie.
I'm okay.
Mommy's okay.
Everything's okay.
All I can say is, "Good riddance."
Ah, look who it is.
So, are you leaving town?
Thanks for your hard work.
Where's the 70 billion?
Where'd you put all that money?
Uh-oh, here we go.
I told you, it's going right
into the country's treasury.
Can you believe this?
Ah, man, look at this guy.
- All right, Colonel Ahn. Got it?
- Yes, sir.
Geez, what a mess, huh?
And what's this?
A token of my gratitude.
Shame to watch you walk around
in that shabby wardrobe
for the rest of your life.
You're a man who's supposed to be
serving his country, after all.
If you're gonna
become a high-power prosecutor
or a bigwig attorney,
you'll need one good suit,
won't you?
Oh, gosh. Well…
You going back?
To Busan, I mean?
Yes.
And what about you? What's your next move?
Excuse me, Colonel Baek?
You have any regrets?
You have to kill Baek Kitae.
That's the only way
you'll survive this now.
And the same goes for your sister
and your little niece.
It's the only way they'll live.
I remember saying something
a while back to Baek Kitae.
Something like…
"Claiming you acted the way you did
because the world is crazy
is nothing more than a flimsy excuse."
At the end of the day,
everyone makes their own choices
in this life.
As for me?
In order to bring him down,
I sold out.
I gave up my own sense of duty
and patriotism to the men in power.
Baek Kitae and I…
both betrayed our values.
And what was it all really for?
-  My friend.
-  Yes, sir.
Keep a close watch on Cho
and report to me regularly.
Of course, sir.
I think it's time to go in, Madam Shin.
'Cause I'm getting impatient.
All right, let's go.
So, I'll be the director?
My friend.